# **Geoffrey T. Perrin**

Github: github.com/gperrin12 | geoffperrin@gmail.com | 734.674.5481 | New York City, NY

### **SUMMARY:**

I'm an experienced data scientist finishing up a master's degree at NYU focusing on using machine learning to solve urban problems.

Specialties: Machine Learning; Random Forest Regression and Classification; Neural Networks / Deep Learning; Computer Vision; Spatial Analysis; Crowd Sourced Data Collection; Cloud Computation; Time Series Analysis; Fourier Transformations.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Programing Languages: R. Python, SAS, Stata, SQL

Programing Tools: Pandas, GeoPandas, Jupyter, Tableau, ArcGIS, Alteryx, Amazon EC2, Amazon RDS for

PostgreSQL, Computer Vision (OpenCV), Deep Learning (Keras)

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

New York City, NY

September 2016 – Present

Capstone project reduces municipalities' departments of transportation costs by 95% in assessing bike lane quality, while time savings run into the thousands of hours. Accomplished through computer vision algorithms, crowd sourced data collection, and cloud computing.

### **NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress**

New York City, NY

Graduate Research Assistant MacArthur Fellow

November 2016 – Present

- Improved the granularity of predicting household waste generation for the Department of Sanitation New York (DSNY) by building a neural network model with an R-squared nearing 0.87.
- Improved NYPD's ability to predict the propensity for a neighborhood to report a shooting incident by building a random forest classification model.

#### **Detroit Land Bank Authority**

Detroit, MI

Bloomberg Fellow

Graduate Student

July 2016 - May 2017

- Reduced foreclosed home pipeline sorting time by 95% by building random forest classification model, which predicts whether or not a home is occupied, with an AUC score of 0.99.
- Reduced decision making time in whether or not a Detroit Land Bank owned property should be demolished by 90% by building random forest classification model, with 96% accuracy.

#### Levi Strauss & Co.

San Francisco, CA

Senior Analyst

July 2013 - July 2016

 Saved LS&Co. \$5 million as measured by sales not lost due to stockouts by building ARIMA time series forecasting models and presenting results through Tableau dashboards.

#### Acumen

San Francisco, CA

Quantitative Analyst II

January 2012 - July 2013

Reduced the time taken in bringing cases to court by DOJ lawyers by 50% by building a logit classifier model detecting providers committing Medicare fraud.

#### **EDUCATION:**

**Masters of Science in Urban Informatics** 

August 2017

New York University - New York, NY

**Bachelor of Science in Economics, Financial Mathematics** University of Michigan - Ann Arbor, MI

May 2009